<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xml:base="https://retirery.lndo.site/rss.xml">
  <channel>
    <title>The Retirery - Retirement jobs, facts, ideas, and tools</title>
    <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/rss.xml</link>
    <description/>
    <language>en</language>
    
    <item>
  <title>Beware of Bias in Retirement Financial Advice</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/beware-bias-retirement-financial-advice</link>
  <description>Retirees have a lot of money and need to suddenly make many complicated and confusing decisions.

At retirement, most people have accumulated more money that at any other time in their life, and they suddenly must make some sophisticated financial decisions about all that money.

Should the 401k they acquired at work be rolled over into an IRA when they retire?
	If so, where should they move it? The institutions that are vying for that money are not exactly impartial about how they compare to their counterparts.
	IRAs have dozens of investment options, and many of them put money in the pocket…</description>
  <pubDate>2017-06-11T13:10:29-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/beware-bias-retirement-financial-advice</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Offer financial advice</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/offer-financial-advice</link>
  <description>Millions of Baby Boomers will be retiring in the next few years, and many of them will be in need of retirement advice. Who better to advise them than someone who has already experienced the problems and opportunities of managing retirement finances? It's also a job that lends itself to part-time work on a schedule that you can control.

Retirement requires lots of critical investment decisions to be made, decisions that most people have never had to deal with before:

Should you roll over your 401k into an IRA when you retire?
	If you roll funds into an IRA, where should you put it, and how…</description>
  <pubDate>2017-06-11T12:42:40-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/offer-financial-advice</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Involuntary Early Retirement</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/involuntary-early-retirement</link>
  <description>An AARP survey reports that 46% of retirees retired earlier than they originally planned. When listing reasons for the early retirement, early retirees listed many that were involuntary or unexpected.

The survey talked to people age 50+, divided between those who are already retired and those who are not yet retired, to try to assess their feelings about retirement. Of the 46% of retirees who retired earlier than planned, the primary reasons for doing so were involuntary.

The involuntary reasons included

Personal health problems
	The need to care for someone else (someone else's health…</description>
  <pubDate>2017-05-19T12:11:59-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/involuntary-early-retirement</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Teach</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/teach</link>
  <description>If you have an area of expertise, and you like explaining things to others, look for an opportunity to teach that skill or topic.</description>
  <pubDate>2017-05-16T20:28:49-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/teach</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Build a small income tax preparation business</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/prepare-income-taxes/build-small-income-tax-preparation-business</link>
  <description>If you have experience in income tax preparation, create a small income tax preparation business. As your own boss, you can select your own clients and your own hours. Keep it simple, you can work at home and get by with not much more than business cards and a computer. Make house calls and meet your clients in their own homes. That will be a nice service and you won't need to set up a fancy office for them to come to.

Market your business by listing it in local newspapers and weekly shopping circulars. Ask friends and family to let others know that you're available.

For less responsibility…</description>
  <pubDate>2017-05-16T19:36:10-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/prepare-income-taxes/build-small-income-tax-preparation-business</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Read "Break Free: The Ultimate Guide to Housesitting"</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/house-sit-watch/read-break-free-ultimate-guide-housesitting</link>
  <description>This book goes into great detail about how to plan a trip where you do house sitting in a remote location as an alternative to booking a hotel room. The book is only available in the Kindle format, but it is part of the Kindle Unlimited package so it's free if you do have a Kindle account.

The author of this book has used this technique extensively to travel and the book is chock full of things to watch out for and ways to improve your odds of landing this kind of opportunity.

Note that there are definitely risks to contracting with strangers in a remote location, so approach this idea…</description>
  <pubDate>2017-05-16T16:18:24-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/house-sit-watch/read-break-free-ultimate-guide-housesitting</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Be Your Own Boss</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/be-your-own-boss</link>
  <description>Running your own business gives you the flexibility to do something that you are passionate about. You can take only the work you want to do, and at the time you want to do it. You'll sacrifice some potential income if you want to take the winter off, but in retirement you may not need as much income as when you had a family depending on you. There are many reasons why you might want to be your own boss in retirement. 

You may have worked for others for many years and always wanted to work for yourself. In retirement you can finally take the plunge.
	Finding a retirement job that allows a…</description>
  <pubDate>2017-05-16T10:08:25-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/be-your-own-boss</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>A Retirement Job Can Stretch Retirement Savings!</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/retirement-job-can-stretch-retirement-savings</link>
  <description>Even a relatively small income from a retirement job has the power to reduce the amount of money you need to retire..

You should have enough sufficient retirement savings that you will not have to withdraw more than 4% of your assets each year to live on. At that rate you should have enough money to last all, or at least most, of the way through your retirement without running out of money.

If you have $500,000 in savings you could pull out 4% a year, or $20,000. To reverse that logic, if you can reduce your withdrawals by $20,000 a year by getting $20,000 from some other source, you could…</description>
  <pubDate>2017-04-20T19:45:27-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/retirement-job-can-stretch-retirement-savings</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>House sit / watch</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/house-sit-watch</link>
  <description>One way to make, or at least save, money is to watch other people's houses while they are away. Activities would include collecting mail and newspapers, taking care of pets, maintaining the house, and making sure the house looks lived-in.

House watching might be done for a fee, where the watcher checks in on a regular basis without actually living in the home. This is a way to make a little income, perhaps watching the homes of snow birds while they are away.

House sitting is a variation where you actually live in the house rent-free, to take care of it while the owners are gone. House…</description>
  <pubDate>2017-03-25T15:14:44-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/house-sit-watch</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Volunteer as a tax preparer</title>
  <link>https://retirery.lndo.site/prepare-income-taxes/volunteer-tax-preparer</link>
  <description>AARP Foundation Tax-Aide offers free tax-filing help to those who need it most. They’re looking for compassionate and friendly individuals to join their team of local volunteers for the tax season. You’ll receive training and continued support in a welcoming environment. And you’ll not only learn new skills, but also get a great feeling from helping someone else.

This is a volunteer opportunity that could also provide the background you need for getting paid work doing income tax preparation.</description>
  <pubDate>2017-03-12T14:13:10-0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Karen Stevenson</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://retirery.lndo.site/prepare-income-taxes/volunteer-tax-preparer</guid>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
